<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>WP do</title>
    <link>https://tbshiki.github.io/wp-do-rss/</link>
    <description>WP do RSS feed</description>
    <docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs>
    <generator>python-feedgen</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 09:08:50 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting on WordCamp Phoenix 2024: Struggles, Successes, and the Road Ahead</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/reflecting-on-wordcamp-phoenix-2024-struggles-successes-and-the-road-ahead</link>
      <description>Seven months ago I registered for &amp;#38; scheduled a trip to Phoenix Arizona for a [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 20:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Photo Festival 2024, A Five Part Retrospective, Part 5, What We Learned, Where We’re Going</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/wordpress-photo-festival-2024-a-five-part-retrospective-part-5-what-we-learned-where-were-going</link>
      <description>In this last episode about the Kerala WPPhotos Festival I talk not only about the project, but also where this project is leading us.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 21:12:01 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gutenberg’s Project Leadership Sits Down with  Outreach Program to Discuss Problems with the Site Editor</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/gutenbergs-project-leadership-sits-down-with-new-outreach-team-to-discuss-problems-with-the-site-editor</link>
      <description>What do you get when you put a handful of outspoken WordPress developers, agencies, product owners, and community advocates on a video call with the Lead Architect and Product Managers of the entire Gutenberg project? Hopefully progress.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 21:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cwicly’s Unexpected Farewell: Founder Decides to Discontinue Development</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/cwiclys-unexpected-farewell-founder-decides-to-discontinue-development</link>
      <description>In a shocking development, the Gutenberg-based page builder Cwicly’s founder Louis-Alexander Désiré has announced that [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 18:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Certain WP Form Plugins Make Accessibility Easy</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/certain-wp-form-plugins-make-accessibility-easy</link>
      <description>Certain WordPress form plugins make achieving accessibility compliance easy. Others...not so much.  This article highlights work that Gravity Forms and other plugins are doing to create more inclusive user experiences.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress Developer Docs Shows Off a New Block-Based Redesign</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/wordpress-developer-docs-shows-off-a-new-block-based-redesign</link>
      <description>WordPress.org relaunched its Developer Documentation with a much more intuitive homepage, cohesive navigation, and a modern design.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 19:03:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synced Pattern Overrides punted, Font Library approved, as WordPress 6.5 nears release</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/synced-pattern-overrides-punted-font-library-approved-as-wordpress-6-5-nears-release</link>
      <description>The Executive Director of WordPress gives the final verdict on two 6.5 features with uncertain futures.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Which WP Theme is Best? Fun With Theme Download Stats</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/which-wp-theme-is-best-fun-with-theme-download-stats</link>
      <description>The article delves into the popularity of WP.org themes, employing a lighthearted approach and original metrics such as "usage rate" and "enthusiasm gap" to assess user preferences and enthusiasm for different WP themes.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 15:11:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordCamp Asia 2025 Scheduled For Next February in Manila, Philippines</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/wordcamp-asia-2025-scheduled-for-next-february-in-manila-philippines</link>
      <description>WordCamp Asia has unveiled its host city for 2025 &amp;#8211; Manila, Philippines. After Bangkok and [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 12:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automattic Doubles Down on the Developer Community</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/automattic-doubles-down-on-the-developer-community</link>
      <description>As the WordPress ecosystem evolves, Automattic is changing its relationship with the developer community.</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:20:41 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matt Mullenweg to Deliver State Of The Word 2024 From Tokyo, Japan</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/matt-mullenweg-to-deliver-state-of-the-word-2024-from-tokyo-japan</link>
      <description>WordPress co-founder Matt Mullenweg announced at the Q&amp;#38;A session of WordCamp Asia 2024 that he [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:35:56 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Surprising Tech Trends in WordPress and Beyond</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/surprising-tech-trends-in-wordpress-and-beyond</link>
      <description>WordPress constitutes 46% of websites, showing stable usage but with a significant portion using outdated software. Competitors like Wix and Squarespace are gaining ground, while PHP and Mailchimp experience decreases in usage.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 08:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bluehost Announced New Cloud Hosting Built on WP Cloud</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/bluehost-announced-new-cloud-hosting-built-on-wp-cloud</link>
      <description>Bluehost, one of the leading web hosting providers, has announced Bluehost Cloud, an innovative cloud-based [&amp;#8230;]</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 12:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The WordPress Training Team’s Big Changes: Learning Pathways and Website Redesign</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/the-wordpress-training-teams-big-changes-learning-pathways-and-website-redesign</link>
      <description>The WordPress Training team is rethinking- and redesigning- how Users, Designers, and Developers can Learn WordPress.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 17:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Block Bindings and Custom Fields –  an (almost) no-code example</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/block-bindings-and-custom-fields-an-almost-no-code-example/</link>
      <description>This article received two updates today, March 13, 2024: With the upcoming release of version 6.5, WordPress will receive the first iteration of Block Bindings API, a way to bind content of blocks to data stored in custom fields. Custom fields have been around for a long time. What wasn&amp;#8217;t available was a way for&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 01:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Synced Pattern Overrides – an early review</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/pattern-overrides-an-early-review/</link>
      <description>Update March 14, 2024: In preparation for WordPress 6.6, Daniel Richards posted an overview issue on what&amp;#8217;s next for Synced Pattern Overrides on GitHub Update March 13, 2024: During the WordPress 6.5 Release cycle, contributors noticed that this feature needs some more refinement and punted it to WordPress 6.6. During beta a change was merged&amp;#160;that&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 01:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#111 – Josepha Haden Chomphosy on Navigating WordPress’ Evolution, Growth and Change</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/111-josepha-haden-chomphosy-on-navigating-wordpress-evolution-growth-and-change</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Josepha is the Executive Director of WordPress, a role she's held since 2019. She's been contributing since 2012 and has a special fondness for brand-new-to-WordPress learners. During the episode Josepha shares her insights on overcoming the challenges posed by the pandemic. She talks about the positive strides made with the Gutenberg project and the need for improved change management during its implementation. We discuss market share of the CMS, community events, and community burnout, as well as how Josepha thinks about measuring WordPress' success, and future goals of the project. If you’re interested in the WordPress project as a whole, and how it’s run and directed, this podcast is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on My 2 Weeks Writing for The Tavern</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/reflections-on-my-2-weeks-writing-for-the-tavern</link>
      <description>What did I learn during my 2 weeks of writing for The Tavern?  Why was it so scary to push the "Publish" button?  How would I improve The Tavern? I reflect on these questions and more!</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 23:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Inside DE{CODE} 2024, WP Engine’s Upcoming Developer Conference</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/inside-decode-2024-wp-engines-upcoming-developer-conference</link>
      <description>WP Engine's team opens up about their annual developer conference focusing on WordPress, AI, and of course, Advanced Custom Fields.</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 15:13:31 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build modern layouts, WordPress 6.5 Dev Notes, Gutenberg in Drupal, Block Bindings and more — Weekend Edition 287</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/build-modern-layouts-wordpress-6-5-dev-notes-gutenberg-in-drupal-block-bindings-and-more-weekend-edition-287/</link>
      <description>Howdy, What a great experience WordCamp Asia and Taipei, Taiwan was! I went a few days early so I could do some sightseeing. The city combines the traditional, the unconventional with the 21st century high-tech vibe. I will share photos and details in the coming weeks. Meanwhile, you can browse the official photo album of&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 03:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gutenberg Changelog #97 – WordPress 6.5, Gutenberg 17.8 and 17.9</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/podcast/gutenberg-changelog-97-wordpress-6-5/</link>
      <description>In this episode, Joni Halabi and Birgit Pauli-Haack discuss WordPress 6.5, Gutenberg 17.8 and 17.9 Show Notes / Transcript Show Notes Joni Halabi, senior developer at Georgetown University What’s new for developers? (March 2024) Developer Hours: Exploring Block Hooks in WordPress 6.5 WordPress 6.5 Gutenberg plugin What’s new in Gutenberg 17.8? (28 February) What’s new&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 11:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#112 – Miriam Schwab on Balancing WordPress Success and Family Life</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/112-miriam-schwab-on-balancing-wordpress-success-and-family-life</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Miriam Schwab. Miriam co-founded Strattic to enable WordPress websites to be more secure and performant. After Elementor acquired Strattic, Miriam continued leading the unit before becoming Head of WordPress Relations. With over 15 years of experience, she's a respected member of the WordPress community and a renowned speaker. In today's episode we discuss Miriam’s life. It’s a departure for this podcast which usually focuses upon the code, the plugins and the community. The idea came out of a talk which Miriam presented at WordCamp Asia this year. In this talk Miriam outlined how she carved out a successful career in the world of WordPress whilst also being the mother of seven children, and it’s fascinating. If you’re interested in hearing how one person has managed the stresses and strains of an incredibly busy life, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 16:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dev hours on Block Hooks, building better patterns, customizing your store, a new book and more — Weekend Edition 288</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/dev-hours-on-block-hooks-building-better-patterns-customizing-your-store-a-new-book-and-more-weekend-edition-288/</link>
      <description>Howdy, Next week is going to be a busy week, with two releases, WordPress 6.5 and Gutenberg 18.0, a Hallway Hangout and Developer Hours. It feels to me that WordPress 6.5, has received a lot of buzz. It&amp;#8217;s a powerful release with lots of great new features, especially for extenders and other developers. I also&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 01:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#113 – Shawn Hooper on Launching WordCamp Canada (WCEH)</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/113-shawn-hooper-on-launching-wordcamp-canada-wceh</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Shawn Hooper. Shawn Hooper is a key figure in the Canadian WordPress community. He’s an advocate for national and local gatherings that bring WordPress enthusiasts together. Later this year, the first ever WordCamp Canada, or WCEH for short, will be held in Ottawa. The event is deep in the planning stages. The venue is secured, the speakers have been finalised, and it’s now up to the team of volunteers, of which Shawn is one, to make the event a success. We get into the challenges of creating an event of this scale. From conception until now, there’s a lot of moving parts. The venue, food, transport, volunteers, sponsors, speakers, the list could go on. It all needs to be planned, tasks assigned and executed. If attending WordPress events, and volunteering your time, is your thing, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 15:18:39 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gutenberg 18.0, Playground, Pattern, and Form plugins and so much more — Weekend Edition 289</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/gutenberg-18-0-playground-pattern-and-form-plugins-and-so-much-more-weekend-edition-289/</link>
      <description>Happy Easter if you celebrate it! 🐰 🐣&amp;#160; The Easter weekend has a total different vibe in Munich as it had in Naples. In Naples, it was just a normal weekend, and you could get groceries over the weekend, and other shopping done. Here it is a four-day weekend with Good Friday and Easter Monday&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 07:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gutenberg Changelog #98 – WordPress 6.5, Gutenberg 18.0 Community Theme Project and the Contributor Mentorship Program</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/podcast/gutenberg-changelog-98/</link>
      <description>In this episode, Maggie Cabrera and Birgit Pauli-Haack discuss WordPress 6.5, Gutenberg 18.0, Community Theme Project and the Contributor Mentorship Program. Show Notes / Transcript Show Notes Maggie Cabrera Announcements Developer Blog updates What’s new in Gutenberg 18.0? (27 March). Story Dataviews Component Design Share: Mar 11-Mar 22 Transcript Birgit Pauli-Haack: Hello, and welcome to&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 19:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#114 – Tammie Lister on the Journey Through Design and Theming</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/114-tammie-lister-on-the-journey-through-design-and-theming</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Tammie Lister. If you’ve been in the WordPress space for a while, Tammie's name is likely a familiar one. She's an 18-year veteran of the project, a talented designer, developer, and a key contributor to the project. Her journey has made her wear a variety of hats in both agency life and product development. Today, Tammie shares insights that span from the practical to the philosophical within the open-source landscape. We get to hear Tammie's perspective on this crucial experimentation phase in WordPress theme development, the balance she seeks between minimalist design and functional complexity, and her active roles, including the default theme task force. Tammie's excitement for what's next is palpable. So, whether you're a developer, a designer, or a WordPress aficionado, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About WordPress 6.5 – all in one list on blocks and site editor</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/about-wordpress-6-5-all-in-one-list/</link>
      <description>This week, WordPress 6.5 certainly dominated the WordPress news cycle. Articles, Videos, Threads on X, and workshops are plenty available for every type of WordPress user. This list of resources if for all who need to dive deeper into certain aspects or have to field questions about the new release. I didn&amp;#8217;t aim for completeness,&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 15:46:32 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 6.5, register Font collections, working with templates, or playground — Weekend Edition 290</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/wordpress-6-5-register-font-collections-working-with-templates-or-playground-weekend-edition-290/</link>
      <description>Howdy, This week, WordPress 6.5 certainly dominated the WordPress news cycle. Articles, Videos, Threads on X, and workshops are plenty available for every type of WordPress user. I compiled a separate list for your perusal or to point people to wandering about. As a reader of this newsletter, you have kept up with all the&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 00:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#115 – Jamie Marsland on Turning Technical Know-How Into Popular Content</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/115-jamie-marsland-on-turning-technical-know-how-into-popular-content</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Jamie Marsland, and he's here to talk to me about his recent journey into YouTube content creation as well as the topic of how WordPress is positioned against the likes of Wix and Shopify. Jamie shares his strategies for effective video creation, from planning to execution, along with his thoughts on sponsored content and its place in the YouTube ecosystem. If you’re curious about the future of WordPress, content creation, or the dynamics of digital learning, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grid Layouts are coming, Playground for preview, Interactivity API in the wild — Weekend Edition 291</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/grid-layouts-are-coming-playground-for-preview-interactivity-api-in-the-wild-weekend-edition-291/</link>
      <description>Howdy, Don&amp;#8217;t forget to save the date for the Hallway Hangout: Let’s chat about what’s next in Gutenberg on April 24 at 11 pm UTC / 7pm EDT / 4 pm PDT / 1 am CEST Rob Cairns and I chatted on his podcast about WordPress 6.5 and beyond. Spring is back in Munich and&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 04:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#116 – Jonathan Desrosiers on the Challenges and Rewards of Contributing to WordPress</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/116-jonathan-desrosiers-on-the-challenges-and-rewards-of-contributing-to-wordpress</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Jonathan Desrosier. Jonathan has been a contributor to WordPress Core for many years, and a WordPress Core committer since 2018. Jonathan currently works as a Senior Software Engineer at Bluehost, where he is sponsored full-time to contribute to WordPress Core through the Five for the Future program. We talk about the challenges that come with contributing to such a large and multi-faceted project, from the intricate process of decision-making, involving many stakeholders, to the occasional moments of feeling demoralised when contributions seem like a drop in the ocean. We discuss the importance of regular contributions, and about the sustainability of the open-source ecosystem, emphasising the critical role businesses need to play, and the potential risks when key contributors step back. If you’re curious about how you can contribute, what that looks likes, and where it can take you, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 14:20:52 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pattern Directory updated, Faster Web w/ WordPress, and Interactivity API in the wild — Weekend Edition 292</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/pattern-directory-updated-faster-web-w-wordpress-and-interactivity-api-in-the-wild-weekend-edition-292/</link>
      <description>Howdy, Greetings from WordCamp Leipzig! I didn&amp;#8217;t get much time to work on this week&amp;#8217;s edition, but I didn&amp;#8217;t take a break either as I found some great articles, videos and tutorial, I wanted you to know about right away. WordCamp Leipzig was a great no-frills WordCamp. I arrived after a workday on Friday night,&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 08:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the latest version of the Create Block Theme plugin</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/exploring-the-latest-version-of-the-create-block-theme-plugin/</link>
      <description>The Create Block Theme plugin was created to streamline block theme development by adding to the power of the Site Editor with theme specific goodies and workflows. The plugin aims to be a modern quick start tool for the world of block themes, allowing you to create your own or build upon existing themes without&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 16:04:09 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#117 – Maestro Stevens on Inclusivity in Website Design Decisions</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/117-maestro-stevens-on-inclusivity-in-website-design-decisions</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Maestro Stevens. Maestro is an international speaker and managing director of The Iconic Expressions. His areas of expertise include digital marketing, brand strategy, web development, and project leadership. In this episode Maestro lays out the case for how inclusivity is not just something that we need to be concerned about at things like events, but also in our WordPress website designs. If you're curious about the intersection of creativity, representation, and the WordPress ecosystem, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#118 – Nahuai Badiola on Digital Sustainability Across the Whole WordPress Project</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/118-nahuai-badiola-on-digital-sustainability-across-the-whole-wordpress-project</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Nahuai Badiola. Nahuai is a freelance WordPress developer, theme, and plugin creator. He also writes WordPress code tutorials and enjoys sharing everything he learns about web sustainability in his blog, podcast, and at WordPress events. Nahuai’s life took an unexpected turn one day when he attended a 10-minute lightning talk at a WordCamp. The content of that talk was web sustainability and it profoundly changed his perspective on how we should view our use of the internet. Nahuai has since been a vocal advocate for sustainability within the WordPress community. Today, Nahuai and I discuss the nuances of the environmental impact of web development with a particular focus on WordPress. We discuss ideas like reducing code in plugins, and highlight the Performance Team's efforts to make WordPress more green. If you're curious about sustainability within WordPress web development, and the community more broadly, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 6.6 Roadmap + demos, what’s next for Meta boxes, Pattern tutorials  — Weekend Edition 293</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/wordpress-6-6-roadmap-demos-whats-next-for-meta-boxes-pattern-tutorials-weekend-edition-293/</link>
      <description>Howdy, Well, this week there has been plenty of information about what WordPress 6.6 might bring. It&amp;#8217;s scheduled to be released in mid-July and will be fully packed with awesome features. The designer tools set for nocode site builders gets massively bigger with Pattern overrides, Grid Layout. Section Styles and Block Style variations. There are&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 04:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gutenberg Changelog #99 – WordPress 6.6 + 6.5.3, Gutenberg 18.1 + 18.2, and Create Block Theme Updates</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/podcast/gutenberg-changelog-99-wordpress-6-6-create-block-theme-updates/</link>
      <description>In this episode, Sarah Norris and Birgit Pauli-Haack discuss WordPress 6.6 and 6.5.3, Gutenberg 18.1 + 18.2 and Create Block Theme Updates Show Notes / Transcript Show Notes Special Guest:&amp;#160;Sarah Norris JavaScript Developer 6.4 editor tech co-lead / Core team rep Announcements Create Block Theme plugin WordPress WordPress 6.5.3 RC1 is now available Gutenberg Interactivity&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 11:13:50 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#119 – Paolo Belcastro on How AI Is Shaping WordPress Wordflows</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/119-paolo-belcastro-on-how-ai-is-shaping-wordpress-wordflows</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Paolo Belcastro.

Paolo works at Automattic, where he’s focused on Jetpack and .blog products. He’s been working remotely since 1994 and managing distributed teams since 1998.

He’s on the podcast today to talk about AI, and he certainly brings a wealth of knowledge and experience in integrating AI with web development.

With Paolo’s insights into the recent advancements in open source AI models and the collaborative efforts within the AI community to keep platforms accessible but innovative, you’ll gain a comprehensive view of where AI in web development stands today and where it might head tomorrow.

If you're a developer, a tech enthusiast, or anyone interested in the intersection of AI and creative processes, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#120 – Alexander Gilmanov on Transitioning From Developer to Entrepreneur</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/120-alexander-gilmanov-on-transitioning-from-developer-to-entrepreneur</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Alexander Gilmanov. Alex comes to us today from Belgrade, Serbia. He’s a full-stack developer with a rich heritage of freelance and agency work. His company officially launched in 2014, and they’ve continued work with clients, as well as creating a range of WordPress plugins, and their own SaaS apps, mainly in the online booking space. If you’re a developer and are in the weeds of writing code, perhaps you’ve thought about a change of direction. We explore Alexander’s transition from hands-on coding to strategic management. It’s a fascinating conversation, and if you’ve wanted to start an agency but have concerns about what that might bring, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 15:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site builders showing off, Gutenberg 18.3, Alternatives to Meta boxes, Blueprint gallery — Weekend Edition 294</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/site-builders-showing-off-gutenberg-18-3-alternatives-to-meta-boxes-blueprint-gallery-weekend-edition-294/</link>
      <description>Howdy, It&amp;#8217;s really fascinating that Germany has four bank holidays in the month of May, all close to the weekends. So we got to make some nice weekend trips. The latest to Venice, Italy visiting the exhibition space of Biennale Arte 20224, with the &amp;#8220;Foreigners Everywhere&amp;#8221;. We saw incredible creative work from many countries around&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 03:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gutenberg Changelog #100 – NASA’s New Website – the Switch to WordPress and Block Editor</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/podcast/gutenberg-changelog-100-nasa-wordpress-block-editor/</link>
      <description>In this episode, Stacy Holtz, Gary Kovar and Birgit Pauli-Haack discuss NASA’s new website &amp;#8211; the switch to WordPress and Block Editor, the scale of the project, the block and theme development, design and migration. Show Notes / Transcript Show Notes Transcript Birgit Pauli-Haack: Hello, and welcome to our hundredth episode of the Gutenberg Changelog&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 21:59:53 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#121 – Alexander Gilmanov on Transitioning From Developer to Entrepreneur. Part 2.</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/121-alexander-gilmanov-on-transitioning-from-developer-to-entrepreneur-part-2</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Alexander Gilmanov, and he's sharing his story of transitioning from freelancer to agency manager, now overseeing a team of 43. With a focus on WordPress ecosystem, Alexander discusses his leadership approach, avoiding negative motivation and instead fostering a culture of trust and positive reinforcement. He elaborates on the nuances of team management and the benefits of smaller, independent teams coordinated across departments like development, marketing, and support. Key tools like Google Suite, Slack, Jira, and Notion are integral to his operations. His story highlights the importance of community engagement, learning from industry leaders, and the necessity of continuously seeking suitable team members for sustainable management.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#122 – Adam Zielinski on How Playground Is Transforming WordPress Website Creation</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/122-adam-zielinski-on-how-playground-is-transforming-wordpress-website-creation</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Adam Zielinski. He works as a WordPress developer at Automattic and in this episode, we talk about Playground, a groundbreaking project that is redefined the way we interact with WordPress. Adam's visionary approach to creating a seamless WordPress experience within a web browser has revolutionised how easy it is to access WordPress. This project really does change the way that WordPress can be used, and there’s so many exciting prospects for how it might shape the future of website design and development. If you're interested in hearing about cutting-edge advancements reshaping the WordPress landscape, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#123 – Jamie Marsland on the WordCamp Europe Speed Building Challenge</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/123-jamie-marsland-on-the-wordcamp-europe-speed-building-challenge</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Jamie Marsland. Jamie runs a WordPress plugin business and has recently become a full-time content creator on YouTube. You might know Jamie from his popular WordPress speed builds on that channel, where contestants have just 30 minutes to build a website from scratch. In this episode, we dive into Jamie’s involvement with WordCamp Europe, where he will be bringing this speed build format to the live stage. Contestants will race against the clock to recreate a pre-built website, all while being interrupted with questions from Jamie and the audience. If you're attending WordCamp Europe or you're just curious about how WordPress can be made fun and engaging, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 6.6 Beta 1, Blueprints to power Playground, Block Bindings API tutorial and so much more —  Weekend Edition 295</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/wordpress-6-6-beta-1-blueprints-to-powered-playground-block-bindings-api-tutorial-and-so-much-more-weekend-edition-295/</link>
      <description>This weekend, my husband I are traveling to Torino, Italy for work. We&amp;#8217;ll do some sightseeing over the weekend, during the week we&amp;#8217;ll start work as early as possible so we can explore the city some more in the afternoon and evening. On Wednesday, I start first meetings around WordCamp Europe. Thursday is Contributor Day&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 11:25:57 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gutenberg Changelog #101 – WordPress 6.6 Beta 1, Gutenberg 18.3, 18.4, 18.5</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/podcast/gutenberg-changelog-101-wordpress-6-6/</link>
      <description>In this episode, Magdalena Paciorek and Birgit Pauli-Haack discuss WordPress 6.6 Beta 1, Gutenberg releases 18.3, 18.4, 18.5 and WordCamp Europe Show Notes / Transcript Show Notes Special Guest: Magdalena Paciorek Upcoming Events WordPress 6.6 Gutenberg Releases Transcript Birgit Pauli-Haack: Hello and welcome to the 101st episode of the Gutenberg Changelog podcast. In today&amp;#8217;s episode,&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 14:13:21 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How AI and ChatGPT enhance WordPress functionality</title>
      <link>https://kinsta.com/blog/chatgpt-wordpress/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, Artificial Intelligence (AI) is emerging as a game-changer and reshaping how content is created, and how websites are built, including WordPress websites. It&amp;#8217;s making it ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com/blog/chatgpt-wordpress/" rel="nofollow"&gt;How AI and ChatGPT enhance WordPress functionality&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Kinsta®&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 15:21:25 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seven talks about blocks, block themes and beyond at WordCamp Europe 2024</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/seven-talks-about-blocks-block-themes-and-beyond-at-wordcamp-europe-2024/</link>
      <description>A curated list of block related talks at WordCamp Europe 2024</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 03:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>#124 – Mina Tamang on SEO Techniques That Prioritise the User Experience</title>
      <link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/124-mina-tamang-on-seo-techniques-that-prioritise-the-user-experience</link>
      <description>On the podcast today we have Mina Tamang, who is an SEO expert at Codewing Solutions. Mina advocates for prioritising user needs over traditional SEO tactics that emphasise keyword ranking. She stresses the importance of integrating user-centric content with core SEO principles, technical optimisations, as well the utility of WordPress plugins. The discussion also addresses the growing role of AI in content creation, and the need to maintain human elements for relatability and accuracy. If you're looking to refine your SEO strategies with a focus on long-term, user-oriented growth, while also navigating the complexities of modern tools and techniques, this episode is for you.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 13:39:48 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A complete guide to building WordPress post templates: Block Editor, Elementor, and more</title>
      <link>https://kinsta.com/blog/wordpress-post-templates/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you want to create truly custom content on your WordPress site, using custom post templates is a great way to ensure that everything you publish ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com/blog/wordpress-post-templates/" rel="nofollow"&gt;A complete guide to building WordPress post templates: Block Editor, Elementor, and more&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Kinsta®&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Search &amp; Replace Everything by WPCode: Bulk Editing in WordPress Made Easy</title>
      <link>https://www.wpbeginner.com/news/introducing-search-and-replace-by-wpcode-wordpress-bulk-editing-made-easy/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to make bulk updates to your WordPress site? Wouldn’t it be nice if you could update hundreds of posts with a single click… without having to update them manually? If you’re like me and most other smart website owners, then you&amp;#8230;&amp;#160;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wpbeginner.com/news/introducing-search-and-replace-by-wpcode-wordpress-bulk-editing-made-easy/"&gt;Read More &amp;#187;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.wpbeginner.com/news/introducing-search-and-replace-by-wpcode-wordpress-bulk-editing-made-easy/"&gt;Introducing Search &amp; Replace Everything by WPCode: Bulk Editing in WordPress Made Easy&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.wpbeginner.com"&gt;WPBeginner&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Send WordPress Emails Using Amazon SES (Step by Step)</title>
      <link>https://www.wpbeginner.com/plugins/how-to-send-wordpress-emails-using-amazon-ses-step-by-step/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you having trouble sending emails from your WordPress site? One easy way to improve WordPress email reliability is by using the Amazon Simple Email Service, which is also known as Amazon SES. In this article, we will show you how to send emails from&amp;#8230;&amp;#160;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wpbeginner.com/plugins/how-to-send-wordpress-emails-using-amazon-ses-step-by-step/"&gt;Read More &amp;#187;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.wpbeginner.com/plugins/how-to-send-wordpress-emails-using-amazon-ses-step-by-step/"&gt;How to Send WordPress Emails Using Amazon SES (Step by Step)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.wpbeginner.com"&gt;WPBeginner&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2024 17:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Repair WordPress Database (6 Easy Methods)</title>
      <link>https://www.wpbeginner.com/beginners-guide/how-to-repair-wordpress-database/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years, many users have reached out to us and our partner companies to ask about fixing broken WordPress databases. Keeping your WordPress website running smoothly requires a healthy database. If your database gets corrupted, then it can lead to many problems, including error&amp;#8230;&amp;#160;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.wpbeginner.com/beginners-guide/how-to-repair-wordpress-database/"&gt;Read More &amp;#187;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.wpbeginner.com/beginners-guide/how-to-repair-wordpress-database/"&gt;How to Repair WordPress Database (6 Easy Methods)&lt;/a&gt; first appeared on &lt;a href="https://www.wpbeginner.com"&gt;WPBeginner&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Streamline your WordPress analytics with Fathom Analytics: A step-by-step guide</title>
      <link>https://kinsta.com/blog/fathom-analytics/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;ve been wrestling with the complexities of Google Analytics 4 (GA4), you&amp;#8217;re not alone. Many find its dense interface a bit much, especially when you&amp;#8217;re ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com/blog/fathom-analytics/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Streamline your WordPress analytics with Fathom Analytics: A step-by-step guide&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com" rel="nofollow"&gt;Kinsta®&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2024 13:47:13 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>WordPress 6.6 Dev Notes, Theme building workflow, Section Styles, dynamic tokens #WCEU — Weekend Edition 296</title>
      <link>https://gutenbergtimes.com/wordpress-6-6-dev-notes-theme-building-workflow-section-styles-dynamic-tokens-wceu-weekend-edition-296/</link>
      <description>Howdy, it&amp;#8217;s been a week that I returned from WordCamp Europe, and I am still looking at photos of Torino, and my notes. There were so wonderful conversations in Torino with colleagues, long-time friends, I made new friends again. You can follow along via my Twitter (now X) feed #WCEU to get a tiny glimpse.&amp;#8230;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2024 02:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
