<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>WP do</title><link>https://tbshiki.github.io/wp-do-rss/</link><description>WP do RSS feed</description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 19:42:23 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>#113 – Shawn Hooper on Launching WordCamp Canada (WCEH)</title><link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/113-shawn-hooper-on-launching-wordcamp-canada-wceh</link><description>On the podcast today we have Shawn Hooper. Shawn Hooper is a key figure in the Canadian WordPress community. He’s an advocate for national and local gatherings that bring WordPress enthusiasts together. Later this year, the first ever WordCamp Canada, or WCEH for short, will be held in Ottawa. The event is deep in the planning stages. The venue is secured, the speakers have been finalised, and it’s now up to the team of volunteers, of which Shawn is one, to make the event a success. We get into the challenges of creating an event of this scale. From conception until now, there’s a lot of moving parts. The venue, food, transport, volunteers, sponsors, speakers, the list could go on. It all needs to be planned, tasks assigned and executed. If attending WordPress events, and volunteering your time, is your thing, this episode is for you.</description><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 15:18:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>#112 – Miriam Schwab on Balancing WordPress Success and Family Life</title><link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/112-miriam-schwab-on-balancing-wordpress-success-and-family-life</link><description>On the podcast today we have Miriam Schwab. Miriam co-founded Strattic to enable WordPress websites to be more secure and performant. After Elementor acquired Strattic, Miriam continued leading the unit before becoming Head of WordPress Relations. With over 15 years of experience, she's a respected member of the WordPress community and a renowned speaker. In today's episode we discuss Miriam’s life. It’s a departure for this podcast which usually focuses upon the code, the plugins and the community. The idea came out of a talk which Miriam presented at WordCamp Asia this year. In this talk Miriam outlined how she carved out a successful career in the world of WordPress whilst also being the mother of seven children, and it’s fascinating. If you’re interested in hearing how one person has managed the stresses and strains of an incredibly busy life, this episode is for you.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 16:19:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WordPressとAstroを組み合わせて静的サイトを構築する方法</title><link>https://kinsta.com/jp/blog/wordpress-astro/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Astroは、高速かつ効率的な静的サイトを構築できる ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com/jp/blog/wordpress-astro/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WordPressとAstroを組み合わせて静的サイトを構築する方法&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com/jp" rel="nofollow"&gt;Kinsta®&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 08:41:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Laravelアプリ開発で単体テストを行う方法とその重要性</title><link>https://kinsta.com/jp/blog/laravel-unit-testing/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;単体テストは、ソフトウェア開発の肝であり、アプリケー ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com/jp/blog/laravel-unit-testing/" rel="nofollow"&gt;Laravelアプリ開発で単体テストを行う方法とその重要性&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com/jp" rel="nofollow"&gt;Kinsta®&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2024 08:25:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WordPress 6.5の新機能（フォントライブラリ、データビュー、Block Bindings API、Interactivity APIなど）</title><link>https://kinsta.com/jp/blog/wordpress-6-5/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;WordPress 6.5がまもなく3月26日にリリ ...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com/jp/blog/wordpress-6-5/" rel="nofollow"&gt;WordPress 6.5の新機能（フォントライブラリ、データビュー、Block Bindings API、Interactivity APIなど）&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://kinsta.com/jp" rel="nofollow"&gt;Kinsta®&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 09:55:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Inside DE{CODE} 2024, WP Engine’s Upcoming Developer Conference</title><link>https://wptavern.com/inside-decode-2024-wp-engines-upcoming-developer-conference</link><description>WP Engine's team opens up about their annual developer conference focusing on WordPress, AI, and of course, Advanced Custom Fields.</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 15:13:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Reflections on My 2 Weeks Writing for The Tavern</title><link>https://wptavern.com/reflections-on-my-2-weeks-writing-for-the-tavern</link><description>What did I learn during my 2 weeks of writing for The Tavern?  Why was it so scary to push the "Publish" button?  How would I improve The Tavern? I reflect on these questions and more!</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 23:29:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>#111 – Josepha Haden Chomphosy on Navigating WordPress’ Evolution, Growth and Change</title><link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/111-josepha-haden-chomphosy-on-navigating-wordpress-evolution-growth-and-change</link><description>On the podcast today we have Josepha Haden Chomphosy. Josepha is the Executive Director of WordPress, a role she's held since 2019. She's been contributing since 2012 and has a special fondness for brand-new-to-WordPress learners. During the episode Josepha shares her insights on overcoming the challenges posed by the pandemic. She talks about the positive strides made with the Gutenberg project and the need for improved change management during its implementation. We discuss market share of the CMS, community events, and community burnout, as well as how Josepha thinks about measuring WordPress' success, and future goals of the project. If you’re interested in the WordPress project as a whole, and how it’s run and directed, this podcast is for you.</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The WordPress Training Team’s Big Changes: Learning Pathways and Website Redesign</title><link>https://wptavern.com/the-wordpress-training-teams-big-changes-learning-pathways-and-website-redesign</link><description>The WordPress Training team is rethinking- and redesigning- how Users, Designers, and Developers can Learn WordPress.</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 17:46:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bluehost Announced New Cloud Hosting Built on WP Cloud</title><link>https://wptavern.com/bluehost-announced-new-cloud-hosting-built-on-wp-cloud</link><description>Bluehost, one of the leading web hosting providers, has announced Bluehost Cloud, an innovative cloud-based [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 12:49:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Surprising Tech Trends in WordPress and Beyond</title><link>https://wptavern.com/surprising-tech-trends-in-wordpress-and-beyond</link><description>WordPress constitutes 46% of websites, showing stable usage but with a significant portion using outdated software. Competitors like Wix and Squarespace are gaining ground, while PHP and Mailchimp experience decreases in usage.</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 08:50:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Matt Mullenweg to Deliver State Of The Word 2024 From Tokyo, Japan</title><link>https://wptavern.com/matt-mullenweg-to-deliver-state-of-the-word-2024-from-tokyo-japan</link><description>WordPress co-founder Matt Mullenweg announced at the Q&amp;#38;A session of WordCamp Asia 2024 that he [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:35:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Automattic Doubles Down on the Developer Community</title><link>https://wptavern.com/automattic-doubles-down-on-the-developer-community</link><description>As the WordPress ecosystem evolves, Automattic is changing its relationship with the developer community.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:20:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WordCamp Asia 2025 Scheduled For Next February in Manila, Philippines</title><link>https://wptavern.com/wordcamp-asia-2025-scheduled-for-next-february-in-manila-philippines</link><description>WordCamp Asia has unveiled its host city for 2025 &amp;#8211; Manila, Philippines. After Bangkok and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 12:48:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Which WP Theme is Best? Fun With Theme Download Stats</title><link>https://wptavern.com/which-wp-theme-is-best-fun-with-theme-download-stats</link><description>The article delves into the popularity of WP.org themes, employing a lighthearted approach and original metrics such as "usage rate" and "enthusiasm gap" to assess user preferences and enthusiasm for different WP themes.</description><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 15:11:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Synced Pattern Overrides punted, Font Library approved, as WordPress 6.5 nears release</title><link>https://wptavern.com/synced-pattern-overrides-punted-font-library-approved-as-wordpress-6-5-nears-release</link><description>The Executive Director of WordPress gives the final verdict on two 6.5 features with uncertain futures.</description><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 18:22:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WordPress Developer Docs Shows Off a New Block-Based Redesign</title><link>https://wptavern.com/wordpress-developer-docs-shows-off-a-new-block-based-redesign</link><description>WordPress.org relaunched its Developer Documentation with a much more intuitive homepage, cohesive navigation, and a modern design.</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 19:03:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Certain WP Form Plugins Make Accessibility Easy</title><link>https://wptavern.com/certain-wp-form-plugins-make-accessibility-easy</link><description>Certain WordPress form plugins make achieving accessibility compliance easy. Others...not so much.  This article highlights work that Gravity Forms and other plugins are doing to create more inclusive user experiences.</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 23:55:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cwicly’s Unexpected Farewell: Founder Decides to Discontinue Development</title><link>https://wptavern.com/cwiclys-unexpected-farewell-founder-decides-to-discontinue-development</link><description>In a shocking development, the Gutenberg-based page builder Cwicly’s founder Louis-Alexander Désiré has announced that [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 18:23:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Gutenberg’s Project Leadership Sits Down with  Outreach Program to Discuss Problems with the Site Editor</title><link>https://wptavern.com/gutenbergs-project-leadership-sits-down-with-new-outreach-team-to-discuss-problems-with-the-site-editor</link><description>What do you get when you put a handful of outspoken WordPress developers, agencies, product owners, and community advocates on a video call with the Lead Architect and Product Managers of the entire Gutenberg project? Hopefully progress.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 21:51:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WordPress Photo Festival 2024, A Five Part Retrospective, Part 5, What We Learned, Where We’re Going</title><link>https://wptavern.com/wordpress-photo-festival-2024-a-five-part-retrospective-part-5-what-we-learned-where-were-going</link><description>In this last episode about the Kerala WPPhotos Festival I talk not only about the project, but also where this project is leading us.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 21:12:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Reflecting on WordCamp Phoenix 2024: Struggles, Successes, and the Road Ahead</title><link>https://wptavern.com/reflecting-on-wordcamp-phoenix-2024-struggles-successes-and-the-road-ahead</link><description>Seven months ago I registered for &amp;#38; scheduled a trip to Phoenix Arizona for a [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 20:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Acquisition Alert: Kestrel Acquires Seven Barn2 Plugins</title><link>https://wptavern.com/acquisition-alert-kestrel-acquires-seven-barn2-plugins</link><description>Katie Keith, CEO of Barn2, announced that Kestrel has acquired seven plugins from her company [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 19:13:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Block Bindings API Brings Dynamic Data to Blocks</title><link>https://wptavern.com/the-block-bindings-api-brings-dynamic-data-to-blocks</link><description>WordPress 6.5 will introduce the Block Bindings API, laying the foundation for connecting blocks with data from custom fields and more.</description><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 17:57:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WordPress Photo Festival 2024, A Five Part Retrospective, Part 4, Next Generation Events</title><link>https://wptavern.com/wordpress-photo-festival-2024-a-five-part-retrospective-part-4-next-generation-events</link><description>In the penultimate episode of this series I talk with Julia Golomb from the WordPress Community Team about Next Generation WordPress Events.  We'll include how the WPPhotos Event was a great template, and other ideas that could come.</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 16:24:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>You Don’t Need to Know Code to Build a Successful WP Plugin Business.</title><link>https://wptavern.com/you-dont-need-to-know-code-to-build-a-successful-wp-plugin-business</link><description>Discover how small WordPress plugin creators are outsmarting industry giants, turning niche solutions into lucrative businesses through innovation, smart marketing, and unwavering perseverance.</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 13:38:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Avada WordPress Theme Patches Arbitrary File Upload Vulnerability</title><link>https://wptavern.com/avada-wordpress-theme-patches-arbitrary-file-upload-vulnerability</link><description>ThemeFusion’s multipurpose WordPress theme Avada has patched an Arbitrary File Upload Vulnerability. Avada is one [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 13:14:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Data Liberation: Meet WordPress.org’s Ambitious Plan for 2024</title><link>https://wptavern.com/data-liberation-meet-wordpress-orgs-ambitious-plan-for-2024</link><description>The open web is under threat. WordPress.org wants to protect it</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 22:27:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WordPress Photo Festival 2024, A Five Part Retrospective, Part 3, Attendees</title><link>https://wptavern.com/wordpress-photo-festival-2024-a-five-part-retrospective-part-3-attendees</link><description>In this episode of the International WPPhotos event we talk to attendees from three different continents about their various experiences.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 21:16:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Automattic Faces Scrutiny Over AI Access Policy</title><link>https://wptavern.com/automattic-faces-scrutiny-over-ai-access-policy</link><description>This article is a joint effort by James Giroux &amp;#38; Jyolsna. After unconfirmed reports of [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 19:11:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>#110 – Thomas J. Raef on the Shift in How Hackers Attack, and How to Protect Your Site</title><link>https://wptavern.com/podcast/110-thomas-j-raef-on-the-shift-in-how-hackers-attack-and-how-to-protect-your-site</link><description>On the podcast today we have Thomas J. Raef. Thomas is the founder of We Watch Your Website, a company that has been removing malware from websites since 2007. During that time he’s seen many changes in the methods hackers use to take over a website, and that’s the focus of the podcast today. With hackers becoming increasingly agile in their tactics, targeting everything from plugins to session cookies, Thomas brings to the table data he’s gathered from 2023 that puts the spotlight on the evolving digital threat landscape. We’re all used to hearing that plugins, themes, and sometimes WordPress Core, are the most likely culprits when something goes wrong. The story goes that out of date code, or a zero day is discovered and leveraged. Whilst Thomas does not doubt that this is true, he’s here to paint a somewhat different picture. A picture which puts the focus upon stolen session cookies as the most important factor in website attacks last year. If you've ever been concerned about the security of your WordPress site or intrigued by the intricacies of cybersecurity, this episode is for you.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 18:27:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Support Inclusion in Tech’ is Fundraising to Sponsor More Marginalized WordPress Contributors</title><link>https://wptavern.com/support-inclusion-in-tech-is-fundraising-to-sponsor-more-marginalized-wordpress-contributors</link><description>Support Inclusion in Tech (SiNC) is now fundraising on the Open Collective (OC) Foundation’s platform. [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 10:51:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Perils of Hiring: A Cautionary Tale from A WordPress Business Owner</title><link>https://wptavern.com/the-perils-of-hiring-a-cautionary-tale-from-a-wordpress-business-owner</link><description>After being in the WordPress world for 15 years, I’ve made some incredible friendships and [&amp;#8230;]</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 01:15:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>